Guide to the Courtland Cox papers, 1963-2021 RL.11350
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Courtland Cox papers
1963-2021
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cox, Courtland, 1941-
RL.11350
3.0 Linear Feet
.05 Gigabytes
Courtland Cox (1941- ) is an African American civil rights activist, former member of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, and a co-founder of the Drum and Spear Bookstore in Washington, D.C. His papers consist of materials related to the Drum and Spear Bookstore and associated organizations, folders related to his tenure as the Secretary General of the Sixth Pan-African Congress in Tanzania, as well as subject files on the civil rights movement in the South during the 1960s. Includes some photographs of events, a photograph album beloning to Cox, and a group of audiocassette recordings as well as electronic records.
Arrangement
Arranged into the following series: Drum and Spear Bookstore, Pan-African Congress, Subject Files, Audiovisual Materials, and Electronic Records.
Historical Note
The Drum and Spear Bookstore was founded in 1968 by SNCC veterans Charlie Cobb, Judy Richardson, Courtland Cox, and Curtis Hayes (later Muhammed), developing out of the civil rights/black power movement in Washington, DC. It specialized in books written by black authors and books on Asian, African, and African American subjects. The founders took the name Afro-American Resources, Inc., and operated Drum and Spear Bookstore, Drum and Spear Press, and the Center for Black Education. The center held classes for community youth and sponsored educational forums and speakers. The Drum and Spear operated from 1371 Fairmont Street, Washington, D.C. NW, until its closure in 1974.
Biographical Note
Courtland Cox was born in 1941 in New York City. While a Howard University student, Cox became a member of NAG and the Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC). He worked with SNCC in Mississippi and Lowndes County, Alabama, was the Program Secretary for SNCC in 1962, and was the SNCC representative to the War Crimes Tribunal organized by Bertrand Russell. In 1963 he served as the SNCC representative on the Steering Committee for the March on Washington. In 1973 Cox served as the Secretary General of the Sixth Pan-African Congress and international meeting of African people in Tanzania. He co-owned and managed the Drum and Spear Bookstore and Drum and Spear Press in Washington, D.C. Cox was appointed by President Clinton to serve as the Director of the Minority Business Development Agency (MBDA) at the Department of Commerce, a position he held until January 20, 2001. He is currently on the board of the SNCC Legacy Project.
[Adapted from the SNCC Legacy Project website, 2019]
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. To access them, listening or viewing copies must be made. Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use these materials.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use these materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Courtland Cox papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from 2016-2019.
Related Materials
The Rubenstein Library also holds the Judy Richardson Papers and the Cleveland Sellers Papers.
Collection Overview
Collection contains materials related to Cox's management of the Drum and Spear Bookstore and Press in Washington, D.C., his tenure as the Secretary General of the Sixth Pan-African Congress in Tanzania, and his collected subject files on the civil rights movement in the South. Non-paper formats include photographs of events, a photograph album belonging to Cox, and a group of audiocassette recordings as well as electronic records.
Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture.
African Americans -- Civil rights -- Southern States; Civil rights workers -- Alabama; Civil rights workers -- Mississippi; Washington (D.C.); Audiocassettes; Photographs; Photograph albums; John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture; Cox, Courtland, 1941-; Drum and Spear Bookstore; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.); Black Panther Party; Pan African Congress; Richardson, Judy; Cobb, Charles E., Jr.
- Drum and Spear Bookstore, 1968-1978; undated; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, administrative files, board meetings, and other items related to the management and operations of the Drum and Spear Bookstore. Materials are described at the item level.
  - Cox to Charles Cobb, 1970 Oct. 1 (Box 1)
  - Charles Cobb to Cox, 1970 Oct. 7 (Box 1)
  - Cox to Charles Cobb, 1970 Oct. 6 (Box 1)
  - Jennifer Lawson to Cox, 1970 Nov. 4 (Box 1)
  - Cox to Charles Cobb, 1970 Nov. 17 (Box 1)
    Draft and typed letter
  - Jane Galvin Lewis to Judy Richardson, 1970 Dec. 11 (Box 1)
  - Cox to Jennifer Lawson, 1970 Nov. 18 (Box 1)
  - Cox to Charles Cobb, 1971 March 4 (Box 1)
  - Alfred Godfrey to Charles Cobb, ca. Spring 1971 (Box 1)
  - Cox to Charles Cobb, 1971 Oct. 15 (Box 1)
  - Imamu Amiri Baraka to Executive Council and Collective Black Publishers, 1972 Nov. 1 (Box 1)
    Photocopy
  - Cox to Charles Cobb, 1971 July (Box 1)
  - Broadside Press to Combined Black Publishers, 1972 Oct. 12 (Box 1)
  - Cox to Charles Cobb, 1972 March 8 (Box 1)
  - Unsigned letter regarding management of bookstore, undated (Box 1)
  - Drum and Spear to "gentlemen" regarding 4th catalogue of books, undated (Box 1)
  - Cox to Charles Cobb, 1971 Jan. 6 (Box 1)
  - Expansion Committee Report from Tommy Gittens, 1969 May 22 (Box 1)
  - Draft of D.C. Plan, edited, undated (Box 1)
  - Contract between Third World Press and Charlie Cobb for Everywhere is Yours, 1971 May 29 (Box 1)
  - Carolyn Carter to board members, 1971 June 4 (Box 1)
  - Stockholders' Agreements, 1973 Aug. 25 (Box 1)
    Austin, Cobb, Cox, Gittens, Henderson, Holloway, Paul, Richardson; draft and final
  - Cox to R.V. Conrad, 1970 April 24 (Box 1)
  - By-Laws of Drum and Spear, undated (Box 1)
    Three versions
  - Certificate and Articles of Incorporation of Drum and Spear, 1970 May 12 (Box 1)
  - Drum and Spear lease agreement, 1969 Dec. 31 (Box 1)
  - Projected budget, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Model Cities Economic Development Corporation correspondence regarding loan agreement, 1972 June 12 (Box 1)
  - Press board meeting agenda, 1972 April 14 (Box 1)
  - Invoice, Georgetown Printing Co., 1970 Nov. 2 (Box 1)
  - Areas of interest list for Drum and Spear, undated; ca. 1972 (Box 1)
  - Pre-meeting information packet, board meeting, 1972 Dec. (Box 1)
  - General press report and recommendations, undated (Box 1)
  - Issues to be raised in the Combined Black Publishes Meeting, undated (Box 1)
    Detroit, MI
  - Procedures for Inventory and Purpose, ca. 1972 (Box 1)
  - The Feminist Press newsletter and correspondence regarding stocking books, 1972 June (Box 1)
  - Newspaper article on Maelezo, 1972 Sept. 9 (Box 1)
    African American-owned bookstore in D.C.
  - Statement of Financial Condition, 1972 July 31 (Box 1)
  - Inventory list, undated (Box 1)
  - Stock Expansion, Lease-hold Improvements, Inventory list, undated (Box 1)
  - "The Book of African Names", undated (Box 1)
  - "The Book of African Names" press release, undated (Box 1)
  - "African Liberation" book press release, undated (Box 1)
  - "The Struggle for Black Education" book press release, undated (Box 1)
  - Charles Cobb interview transcript, undated (Box 1)
    Topic focuses on Africa
  - Projections for 1973, undated (Box 1)
  - Norman Bernstein Management Inc. to Drum and Spear Bookstore regarding debt, 1972 Nov. 13 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting agenda, 1971 June 5 (Box 1)
  - List of publishers owed $100 or less, 1971 Feb. 23 (Box 1)
  - Profit/loss statement, 1972 Jan. 1-29 (Box 1)
  - Robert H. Neuman to Cox regarding Zambian Roads to Humanism, 1973 Oct. 30 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting agenda, 1972 April /May (Box 1)
  - Table Ordering Priorities for Promotion and Distribution, undated (Box 1)
  - Income statement, 1970 Dec. 31 (Box 1)
  - List of publishers owed, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Press board meeting minutes, 1972 April 14 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1972 May 4 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1973 July 29 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Jeopardy assessment, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Quarterly federal tax return, first quarter, 1970 March 31 (Box 1)
  - Quarterly federal tax return, second quarter, 1970 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Quarterly federal tax return, third quarter, 1970 Sept. 30 (Box 1)
  - Quarterly federal tax return, fourth quarter, 1970 Dec. 31 (Box 1)
  - Notice of district tax lien, 1974 June 12 (Box 1)
    2 versions
  - Statement to correct information, tax form 941C, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Paid bill to Riggs National Bank, 1974 Sept. 19 (Box 1)
  - List of bills, undated (Box 1)
  - "East Africa Through Maps", undated (Box 1)
  - Study guide for The Choice by Samuel F. Yette, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1968 July 3 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1968 June 4 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1968 July 15 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1968 July 31 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1968 Aug. 23 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1968 Sept. 23 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1968 Oct. 3 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 Nov. 25 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1968 Dec. 3 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 Jan. 4 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 Jan. 18 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 Feb. 1 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 Feb. 28 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 March 17 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Memo from Charles Cobb, 1969 March 20 (Box 1)
  - Retreat session, board of Afro-American Resources, 1969 March 22-26 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 April 12 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 June 7 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 July 9 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Resources meeting agenda, 1969 Aug. 13 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 Sept. 21 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 Oct. 20 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 Nov. 3 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1969 Nov. 25 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1970 Jan. 27 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1970 Feb. 16 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1970 March 18 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1970 April 27 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1970 May 18 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1970 Sept. 14 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1970 Sept. 9 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1970 Sept. 23 (Box 1)
  - Bookstore weekly report, undated (Box 1)
  - Salary policy recommendations memo, Salary Review Committee, 1970 Nov. 18 (Box 1)
  - Sales reports, 1970 Oct. (Box 1)
  - Self-sufficiency of Drum and Spear press memo, 1970 Sept. 9 (Box 1)
  - Financial breakdown of maximum cost of (one) record production, undated (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1970 Oct. 5-13 (Box 1)
  - Memos regarding operations, bookstore, communications, export-import, 1970 Oct. 14 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1970 Oct. 20 (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Reources Board meeting minutes, 1970 Oct. 26 (Box 1)
  - Board meeting memo, 1972 Jan. 1 (Box 1)
  - Memo regarding Association for the Study of Negro Life and History (ASNLH) from Anne Holloway, undated (Box 1)
  - Agenda for North American Planning Committee meeting, 1971 Dec. 18 (Box 1)
  - "We Shall Not Be Moved:" The Life and Times of S.N.C.C., Conference at Trinity College (Conn.), 1988 Apr. 14-16 (Box 1)
    Program packet
  - Speech by James Forman to the Black Caucus of NCNP Convention, 1967 Sept. 2 (Box 1)
  - Brochure regarding Puerto Rico/Hartford 15, ca. 1988 (Box 1)
  - UMOJA SASA, vol. 5, issue 2, 1978 Nov. 4 (Box 1)
  - Margaret A. Reid to Cox, 1973 Jan. 5 (Box 1)
  - East African Income Tax Claim for Allowances, undated (Box 1)
  - Drum and Spear financial statement, 1971 Dec. 20 (Box 1)
  - East African Tax Department to Drum and Spear, 1972 Feb. 14 (Box 1)
  - Drum and Spear financial statements in 1971 for East African Income Tax, 1972 Feb. 1 (Box 1)
  - Drum and Spear financial statements in 1971 for East African Income Tax, 1971 Dec. 20 (Box 1)
  - East African Income Tax Department credit slip paying book, 1971 Dec. 22 to 1972 May 9 (Box 1)
  - Milton Coleman to Cobb, 1971 Jan. 8 (Box 1)
  - Invoics, East African Publishing House, 1970 Dec. 30 (Box 1)
  - Application for export licence with Tanzania, 1970 July 6 (Box 1)
  - Cobb to Regional Land Officer, Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania, 1970 Oct. 28 (Box 1)
    Final and copy with edits
  - Cobb to Regional Land Officer, Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania regarding entry permit, 1971 Apr. 15 (Box 1)
  - Cobb to Same Secondary School regarding athletic equipment, 1971 Sept. 1 (Box 1)
  - Embassy of Lesotho to Milton Coleman, 1971 Oct. 29 (Box 1)
  - National Bank of Commerce Statement, 1971 Aug. 12 (Box 1)
  - Center for Black Education to Cobb, 1970 Nov. 12 (Box 1)
  - Regional Land Officer, Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania to Drum and Spear regarding entry permits, 1971 July 12 (Box 1)
  - John Holness to Cobb, 1970 Oct. 14 (Box 1)
  - Unsigned letter regarding Children of Africa printing, 1971 July 20 (Box 1)
  - Memo regarding Regional Land Officer in Tanzania and Drum and Spear Press, undated (Box 1)
  - Cobb to Regional Land Officer, Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania, undated (Box 1)
  - Project outline, undated (Box 1)
  - Introduction and scope of system to be designed for Afro-American Resources, undated (Box 1)
  - Letter from Regional Land Officer, Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania, undated (Box 1)
  - National Printing Company to Cobb regarding Children of Africa printing, 1971 June 15 (Box 1)
  - Memo to parents, undated (Box 1)
  - Unsigned memos, undated (Box 1)
  - Regional Land Officer, Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania to Drum and Spear regarding Jennifer Lawson, 1971 March 29 (Box 1)
  - B.J. Amuli Architexts to Drum and Spear, 1970 Nov. 20 (Box 1)
  - Cobb to Commissioner for Lands, Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania, 1970 Dec. 12 (Box 1)
  - Application for Jennifer Lawson entry permit to Tanzania, 1971 April 15 (Box 1)
  - Cobb to Gera Salo, 1971 Sept. 28 (Box 1)
  - Cobb to C.Y. Mgonja, Minister of Education, Tanzania, 1971 Sept. 23 (Box 1)
  - East African Tax Department forms, undated (Box 1)
  - Assorted invoices and tax receipts, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Regional Land Officer, Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania to Drum and Spear, 1971 March 25 (Box 1)
  - Social Resources and Institutional Development Projects in the Black Community, Afro-American Resources Proposal, undated (Box 1)
  - Sales notes "Actual Activities", undated (Box 1)
  - Quotation from National Printing Company for printing Children of Africa, 1970 Dec. 14 (Box 1)
  - Commissioner for Lands, Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania to Drum and Spear regarding right of occupancy acceptance letter for land, 1971 Jan. 8 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
    Two photographs featuring Courtland Cox and Charles Cobb Jr. from their time together at Drum & Spear.
  - Drum and Spear Bookstore, financial and other records, 1970s (Box 7)
- Pan-African Congress, 1967-1978; undated; 2
  - Proposal for the establishment of the Tanzanian Consulting Council of the Pan-African Skills Project, 1970 Nov. 30 (Box 1)
  - Liberation Struggle newspaper, 1973 Jan.-Feb. (Box 1)
  - Daily News Tanzania, 1975 Nov. 12 (Box 1)
  - Dr. C.L.R. James talks to Geri Stark, Transcript, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
    Two copies, one in English and one in French
  - Message from President Sekou Toure for the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
  - Economic Committee Report from the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
    Includes two copies with edits
  - President Nyerere's speech from the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19 (Box 1)
  - General Declaration from the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
  - Resolution on the French Colonies from the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
  - Science and Technology Committee report from the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
  - Address by the Frelimo Delegation at the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
  - Untitled Speech, undated (Box 1)
  - Article excerpt on the Pan-African Congress, undated (Box 1)
  - Economic Development through Self-Reliance: the Tanzanian Experience, undated (Box 1)
  - Call for a New Africa Statement of Pan Africanist Congress of Azania (South Africa), 1974 June (Box 1)
  - "Water Resources for Agricultural Development," Sudan Delegation, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
    By Mohamed Asakir
  - Africa and the Unity of African Peoples, undated (Box 1)
  - "Technology and Development of Natual Resources, An Overview", 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
    By William A. Douglas
  - "African Unity: Institutions" by Mr Onu, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
  - Statement by Charles C. Diggs, Jr. at the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
  - Statement by Comrade Moukoueke, Secretary of the Congolese Labor Party, Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
  - Proposal for Association of Scientists and Technologists for Pan-African Development, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
  - Pan-African Imperative for Increased Emphasis on Science and Technology, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
    Includes two copies with different type settings
  - Science and Technology Committee C, Preamble and resolutions, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
    Includes copies with edits
  - Declaration of the Liberation Struggle in Southern Africa, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
    Copy with edits
  - Report to President Nyerere by Courtland Cox, Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 1)
  - Steering Committee meeting minutes, Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 May 11 (Box 1)
  - Background History of Pan-African conference, undated (Box 1)
    Two copies, one with edits
  - Assorted reports, Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 2)
  - Resolution, Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 2)
  - List of speeches and papers delivered at Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 2)
  - Working Paper on Desireable Results of the Sixth Pan-African Congress, undated (Box 2)
  - "Pan-African Congress Failed to Fulfill Promise of Earlier Session", 1974 July 26 (Box 2)
    By Earl Ofari
  - Steeting Committee internal memos, undated (Box 2)
  - Secretariat Committee meeting minutes, 1972 May 28 (Box 2)
  - Julian Ellison, Associate Secretary General to Leo Beranek, WCVB-TV, Boston regarding broadcast of Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 Aug. 8 (Box 2)
  - Goals, Science and Technology Area, Pan-African Secretariat, undated (Box 2)
  - Temporary Secretariat Steering Committee list, undated (Box 2)
  - Draft call for Sixth Pan-African Congress, undated (Box 2)
  - Responses to President's opening address to the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19 (Box 2)
  - Reports on D.C. support of anti-apartheid measures, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Caribbean Steering Committee Correspondence of C.L.R. James, 1974 May 28 to July 12 (Box 2)
  - Report, Proceedings and Resolutions of the North American Region Planning Conference for the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1973 May 11-13 (Box 2)
  - Jamaican Declaration, undated (Box 2)
  - News Digest, Interview with C.L.R. James, 1973 Oct. (Box 2)
  - Statistics on African Countries, undated (Box 2)
  - Lists of delegates for the Sixth Pan-African Congress, undated (Box 2)
  - Furniture and equipment inventory, 1974 July 18 (Box 2)
  - Articles by Courtland Cox, photocopies, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "The Pan African Movement", undated (Box 2)
    By W.E.B. DuBois
  - The Call, Sixth Pan-African Congress, undated (Box 2)
  - Background of Pan-African Congress, undated (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1974; undated (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings photocopies, 1974; undated (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings photocopies, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "How American Secret Agents Operate in Africa", undated (Box 2)
    By Kweku Dadson
  - Working Paper for an Association of Scientists and Technologists, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 2)
  - Interview with Dr. Girvan, transcript, undated (Box 2)
  - Report for Black Ministries on the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1973 Sept. 21 (Box 2)
  - Special Communique on the Recent Atrocities and Manoeuvres of Portuguese Colonialism in Mozambique, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 2)
  - Pan-African Skills Project brochure: Employment Opportunities for Peoples of African Descent in the Motherland, undated (Box 2)
  - Resolution on the Caribbean, Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 2)
  - General report of the Caribbean and South American Regional Planning Conference for the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1973 Feb. 14-19 (Box 2)
  - Memorandums on the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1973; undated (Box 2)
  - "National and International Distribution of Black Merchandise", undated (Box 2)
    By Mwalimu Edward Vaughn
  - Cox Correspondence for Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1973 Oct. 18-22 (Box 2)
  - Report for American and Caribbean Ambassadors, 1974 June 3-13 (Box 2)
  - Pan-African Congress book press release, undated (Box 2)
  - Sixth Pan-African Congress press release, undated (Box 2)
  - A Briefing Paper, Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1974 June 3-13 (Box 2)
  - Planning Committee minutes, Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1971 Dec. 18 (Box 2)
  - Form letter, Sixth Pan-African Congress, undated (Box 2)
  - Outline of Proposal for Pan-African Center for Science and Technology, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled notes, undated (Box 2)
  - Speech outline for Cox at MIT Community Fellows on Sixth Pan-African Congress, undated (Box 2)
  - Agenda for the conference, undated (Box 2)
  - Sixth Pan-African Congress program, 1974 June 19-27 (Box 2)
  - The Pan Africanist, 1973 Spring (Box 2)
  - The Jamaica Planning Conference for the Sixth Pan-African Congress agenda, 1973 Feb. 14-20 (Box 2)
  - Assorted notes, undated (Box 2)
  - Monthly report, 1973 Aug. (Box 2)
  - Summary of the address at the North American Region Planning Conference, 1973 May 11 (Box 2)
  - Second Caribbean and South American Reiognal Conference for the Sixth Pan-African Congress, 1973 Dec. 14-16 (Box 2)
  - Sixth Pan-African Congress administrative budget, 1973 Oct.-Dec. (Box 2)
  - Guidelines for organization of North American districts, 1973 July 24 (Box 2)
  - Cox to C.J. Iddy, 1972 Sept. 28 (Box 2)
    Draft and typed copy
  - Partial list of sponsers issuing the call for the Sixth Pan-African Congress, undated (Box 2)
  - Letter to Cox, 1973 Aug. 25 (Box 2)
  - Map of Dar Es Salaam University, Tanzania, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Speech of the Pan-African Congress of Azania, undated (Box 2)
  - Closing session program, Sixth Pan-African Congress, undated (Box 2)
  - Video tape copyright agreement, Howard University and Sixth Pan-African Congress, undated (Box 2)
  - Notes on envelope, undated (Box 2)
  - Letter from Clarence E. Swansten, Congress of Racial Equality, 1973 Jan. 16 (Box 2)
  - Sixth Pan-African Congress to Professor Abdias Do Nascimento, 1973 Feb. 18 (Box 2)
  - Letter to Winston Wiltshire, 1972 Dec. 24 (Box 2)